COLOCIOIU MARIUS

Frontend Engineer

SUMMARY

I'm an enthusiastic and outgoing person, with a passion for Web Development and an eye for detail. With over 10 years of coding experience, I've noticed Frontend work requires a little bit extra, it needs a sense of beauty, symmetry and coherence. It needs style!

- **a** Bucharest, Romania
- mariuscolocioiu@gmail.com
- +4 0767 984 678

EDUCATION

Master's degree, Computer Science

Bucharest Academy of Economic Studies

CSIE, October 2011 - June 2013

SKILLS

HTML5 BOOTSTRAP
CSS3 REST API
SASS GIT
JAVASCRIPT A11Y
REACT SEO
REDUX FIGMA

EXPERIENCE

Frontend Engineer

Rebag, USA

August 2014 - Present

- Wrote clean, maintainable, and efficient code using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Developed responsive web interfaces ensuring they worked seamlessly across various devices, browsers and resolutions.
- Translated design mockups and wireframes into interactive, visually appealing web pages.
- Enforced WCAG accessibility and SEO best practices.
- Worked closely with backend developers, designers, and product owners to properly integrate frontend components.
- Optimized frontend code and assets for better performance and faster page loading.
- Successfully migrated our legacy jQuery codebase to React.

FIFA Ultimate Team Web App QA Lead

Electronic Arts, USA

June 2010 - July 2014

- Planned and allocated QA resources in order to meet project deadlines and goals.
- Oversaw the creation of effective and comprehensive test cases that covered all aspects of software functionality.
- Successfully identified and mitigated potential risks related to software quality, preventing production issues.

INTERESTS

Established user on StackOverflow with over 1,000 reputation (top ~20%).

LeetCode challenge enjoyer.

Keeping up to date with best practices and design patterns.